#### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/jessica-hong-8139a817 (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Management Consulting Business Strategy Business Planning

### Languages

Bahasa Malaysia (Full Professional) English (Full Professional)

# Jessica Hong

Training Consultant at Freelance, self-employed Kuala Lumpur

## Summary

Jessica Hong CA(M) CPA

Jessica always delivers her financial skills programmes in a refreshing way, and helps accelerate the learning curves of the non-finance professionals. Financial courses need not be dull and boring; they can be fun, stimulating and personally motivating.

Jessica Hong (Ms.) is a Malaysian Chartered Accountant and holds a Bachelor of Accountancy from University of Malaya and she completed her post-graduate studies in Management Development Programme at INSEAD, Singapore.

Her career with PricewaterhouseCoopers (PwC) has given her invaluable experience in system assurance, management assurance, audit, fraud investigations, system implementations, due diligence and many other challenging assignments.

She was trained by Michael Wells, Director, IFRS Education Initiative, IFRS Foundation and Paul Pacter, IASB Member & Chairman of the SME Implementation Group in Singapore recently, to be an IFRS Trainer (IFRS is International Financial Reporting Standard).

She is on the panel of trainers for Institute of Singapore Chartered Accountants (ISCA) Business Ethics and Conduct, specialising in Anti Money Laundering and Anti Terrorism Financing topics, and Financial Reporting Standards.

She is appointed by the Accountant's General, Ministry of Finance to train all accountants and operations leaders in Malaysia Government in implementing Malaysia Public Sector Accounting Standards (MPSAS) by 2015, a migration from cash accounting to accrual accounting.

Jessica has varied and vast commercial experience in developing and implementing credit control policies, project management, debt recovery training, system integration and many other management effectiveness & efficiency assignments.

- (1) Financial Analysis for Non-Financial Managers
- (2) Investment Evaluation & Choices
- (3) Financial Modelling
- (4) Business Risk Management
- (5) Credit Risk Management
- (6) Debt Negotiation & Collection
- (7) Financial Reporting Standards –IPSAS, IFRS and IFRS for SMEs

# Experience

Freelance, self-employed
Training And Development Consultant
January 2018 - Present (4 years)
Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

# Finet Associates Consultant January 2006 - December 2017 (12 years)

**PwC** 

Team Lead 1996 - 2001 (5 years)

Lead teams in various assignments

- Audit
- Investigations
- Corporate Valuation
- Forensics

#### Managing Clients

- Slme Darby
- DKSH
- Amoco Chemicals
- RHB Bank

- Felda
- Mycom Group
- Bata

# Education

## **INSEAD**

Management Development Programme, Business, Management, Leadership and Finance  $\cdot$  (2001 - 2001)

Universiti Malaya